Miguel Garcia

Gonzales, CA · miggarcia2207@gmail.com · (831) 774-3098

Career Objective

Hard-working individual who brings positive energy and exceptional work ethic to any environment. Works well with others and is always willing to assume a leadership role if necessary. Interested in gaining experience in data analytics.

EDUCATION

CSU, MONTEREY BAY SEASIDE, CA

B.S. Business Administration, Agribusiness Concentration

May 2022

- **GPA**: 3.59
- **Relevant Coursework:** Fundamentals of Marketing, Integrated Marketing Communications, Information Systems for Decision Making, Bus Analytics Fundamental, Bus Ethics in Action
- Awards: Cum Laude (2022), Jane Pere Johnson Scholarship (2021), Manns Packing Scholarship (2020), Tanimura and Antle Scholarship (2019), Dean's List (2021)
- Extracurricular: Vice President & Treasurer Agribusiness Club, Major Mentor CAMP

EXPERIENCE

Dole Fresh Vegetables

MARINA, CA

Logistics Coordinator

May 2022 - Present

- Ran daily reports to check for late deliveries, pickups, and pending loads.
- Communicated with carriers and plants
- Reported weekly on KPI's to higher management
- Encouraged timely and relevant audits
- Worked with systems such as TMS, YMS, Sensi Tech, and MainFrame
- Made the company over \$15,000 in non compliant trailer charges

Tanimura & Antle SPRECKLES, CA

HR Data Analyst Intern

February 2022 - May 2022

- Expedited new hire packets on to ES1 system
- Assisted with front desk
- Checked and Balanced calculations with payroll
- Attended employee orientations

COLLEGE ASSISTANCE MIGRANT PROGRAM

SEASIDE, CA

Retention Peer Mentor

August 2019 - February 2022

- Directly advised 20 first year college students a semester with FAFSA, registration, applications, scholarships, and college life skills
- Held 1:1 monthly peer mentoring meetings with students to discuss educational and personal progress
- Sent out weekly newsletters that included scholarships, internships, job opportunities, and updates
- Coordinated events

SKILLS

- Languages: Spanish (fluent), English (fluent)
- MS Office Suite, Advanced user of Excel, Customer Service, Teamwork, Google Suite, KPI Management, Google Ads Certification 2019), Digital Marketing and E-commerce Google Certificate (In progress), Data Analytics Certificate (In Progress).